<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
                            <!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
                            <topic id="k1231282" xml:lang="en-us"><title class="- topic/title ">Glass Cube Polishing</title><body><p>Abrasives and polishing removes layers of surface deformation and exposes the material structure for analysis. </p><ul><li>Polishing should be performed for the minimum amount of time required to achieve the desired results. </li><li>Over-polishing can damage the sample.</li><li>After <xref href="#_1._Glass_Cube">collecting a glass cube sample</xref>, see the following:</li></ul><ol><li>Use the Buehler<ul><li>EcoMet 30 Manual Single Grinder Polisher.</li></ul><p><fig id="n9049388"><image href="media/image17.png"/></fig></p></li><li>&amp;nbsp;<table><tgroup cols="2"><colspec colname="c1"/><colspec colname="c2"/><tbody><row><entry><p><fig id="s9862172"><image href="media/image18.jpg"/></fig></p></entry><entry><p><b>PPE Required</b>: Cut resistant gloves.</p></entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table><p>Gather the tools and equipment needed for polishing.</p><ul><li>Polisher machine </li><li>Grinder pads </li><li>Microcloth pad </li><li>Pad removal stick </li><li>Cerium solution</li></ul></li><li>Select the best sample for the polishing and color measurements.<ul><li>Taken on the same day and time.</li></ul></li><li>&amp;nbsp;<table><tgroup cols="2"><colspec colname="c1"/><colspec colname="c2"/><tbody><row><entry><p><fig id="j7361515"><image href="media/image19.jpg"/></fig></p></entry><entry><p><b>PPE Required</b>: Cut resistant gloves.</p></entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table><p>Use the glass cutter or plier tool and remove any excess of glass from the glass cube sample.</p></li><li>&amp;nbsp; <table><tgroup cols="2"><colspec colname="c1"/><colspec colname="c2"/><tbody><row><entry><p><fig id="b8792262"><image href="media/image20.jpg"/></fig></p></entry><entry><p><b>PPE Required</b>: Cut resistant gloves.</p></entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table><p>Use the grinder stone and water. </p><ul><li>Remove any sharp edges from the top of the glass cube sample.</li></ul></li><li>Start with course pads and follow with finer pad.<ul><li>Finish with the micro cloth pad and cerium solution for the final glow.</li></ul><p>Coarse to fine DGD pads:</p><ul><li>Green 240 µm </li><li>Black 125 µm </li><li>Red 75 µm </li><li>Yellow 35 µm </li><li>White 15 µm </li><li>Blue 8 µm</li><li>Micro-cloth PSA pad</li></ul><note><p>Note: Ineffective polishing can cause excessive scratching, comet tails, relief, smearing, edge rounding, and embedding.</p></note><ul><li>These issues can lead to inaccurate readings and results.</li></ul><p><fig id="y8082770"><image href="media/image21.png"/></fig></p></li><li>Place the DGD pad on the polisher plate.<p><fig id="r8193190"><image href="media/image22.png"/></fig></p></li><li>Turn on the polisher.<ul><li>The On-Off switch is located in the back of the equipment.</li></ul><p><fig id="p6739711"><image href="media/image23.png"/></fig></p></li><li>Turn the Power Switch to On to start the plate spinning.<ul><li>Select the RPM (300 RPM recommended).</li><li>Switch the water to Active.</li></ul><note><p>Note: Water should be active when using the DSD pads.</p></note><p>If final polishing, see step 14.<fig id="y4249255"><image href="media/image24.png"/></fig></p></li><li>&amp;nbsp;<table><tgroup cols="2"><colspec colname="c1"/><colspec colname="c2"/><tbody><row><entry><p><fig id="h1148184"><image href="media/image25.jpg"/></fig></p></entry><entry><p><b>PPE Required</b>: Cut resistant gloves for Green 240 µm pads.</p></entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table><p>Hold the glass sample firmly from the top and side surfaces.</p><ul><li>Place the sample on the moving pad, close to the center. </li><li>Hold the sample. Maintain the same pressure.</li></ul><p>Move the sample from the center to the edge of the pad in the transversal direction of the plate movement.</p><ul><li>Repeat the movement 10 times.</li><li>Rotate the sample 90° and repeat the grinding movement 10 times.</li></ul><p>Repeat the movement set 2 additional times to evenly grind the surface of the sample.</p><note><p>Note: Use special care so that the sample does not escape from your hands or stumble with the pad.</p></note><p><fig id="m8979381"><image href="media/image26.png"/></fig></p></li><li><b>&amp;nbsp;</b><table><tgroup cols="2"><colspec colname="c1"/><colspec colname="c2"/><tbody><row><entry><p><fig id="m0542363"><image href="media/image27.jpg"/></fig></p></entry><entry><p><b>PPE Required</b>: Cut resistant gloves for Green 240 µm pads.</p></entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table><p>Turn over the glass sample to the opposite surface and repeat step 10.</p><ul><li>Use both hands to hold the sample and apply even pressure to the surfaces.</li></ul><p>The sample should be polished at least on both surfaces of the lager dimensions.</p><ul><li>It is recommended for the light from the spectrophotometer to pass through the larger dimensions of the sample. Both polished faces should be flat and perpendicular to the light.</li></ul><p><fig id="h6434714"><image href="media/image28.png"/></fig></p></li><li>When the polish is finished:<ul><li>Set the sample aside.</li><li>Turn off the water switch.</li><li>Let the pad rinse for a couple of seconds and turn off the power switch.</li></ul></li><li>Use the pad removal stick to remove the pad.<ul><li>Dry the pad and set it aside.</li><li>Change the finer grade.</li><li>Repeat steps 9-12.</li></ul><note><p>Note: Use the removal stick to reduce the likelihood of damaging the pad.</p></note><p><fig id="o5010405"><image href="media/image29.png"/></fig></p></li><li><b>Final Polish</b><p>Exchange the last DGD pad (blue 8 µm) with the PSA Microcloth pad.</p><ul><li>Wet the pad.</li><li>Turn off the water.</li><li>Add cerium solution to the pad.</li></ul><p>Polish the glass sample as in steps 10-11.</p><ul><li>Apply additional pressure to the sample while polishing.</li><li>Repeat the final polish on the desired surfaces.</li></ul><p>If the pad gets dry:</p><ul><li>Wet the pad.</li><li>Turn off the water.</li><li>Add additional cerium solution.</li></ul><note><p>Note: Use special care so that the sample does not escape from your hands or stumble with the pad cloth.</p></note><p><fig id="x4573781"><image href="media/image30.png"/></fig></p></li><li>The cloth should be visibly wet without casting off when rotating.<ul><li>Maintain the cerium solution throughout the polishing cycle.</li><li>Too little causes heat damage, reduces polishing, and damages the pad.</li><li>Too much causes hydroplaning, reduces polishing, and wastes abrasive.</li></ul></li><li>Rinse the sample and verify that it has the correct polish.<ul><li>Repeat polishing if needed.</li></ul><p><fig id="m0696611"><image href="media/image31.png"/></fig></p></li><li>Rinse the PSA Microcloth pad after polishing.<ul><li>Dry the pad.</li><li>Properly store all DGD and PSA Microcloth pads.</li></ul><p>Continue to <xref href="#_3._Consumables">Consumables</xref>.</p></li></ol></body></topic>