<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
                            <!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
                            <topic id="i4309465" xml:lang="en-us"><title class="- topic/title " id="_Toc171695891">Manual Setup</title><body><p>There are two steps to setting up your wireless router:</p><ol><li>Connect the router to the ADSL or cable modem, and connect a computer to the router.<note><p><b>Note</b>: Your computer has to be set to automatically get its TCP/IP network settings from the router via DHCP. This is usually the case. If your are unsure about this, use the wizard on the CD which automatically takes care of this for you, or refer to the documentation for your computer.</p></note></li><li>Configure the router to use your Internet service.<p id="_Toc171616974"><b>To Connect Your Wireless Router</b></p></li><li>Connect the wireless router, the computer, and the modem.<ol><li>Turn off your computer.</li><li>Turn off and unplug the cable or ADSL broadband modem.</li><li>Locate the Ethernet cable (1) that connects your computer to the modem.<p><fig id="q0400857"><image href="media/image3.png"/></fig></p><p>Figure 1-4</p></li><li>Disconnect the cable at the computer end only (2).</li><li>Securely insert the Ethernet cable from your modem into the Internet port of the wireless router (3).<p><fig id="c3400513"><image href="media/image4.png"/></fig></p><p>Figure 1-5</p></li><li>Securely insert the blue cable (4) that came with your wireless router into a LAN port on the router such as LAN port 1 (5), and the other end into the Ethernet port of your computer (6).<p><fig id="y0683604"><image href="media/image5.png"/></fig></p><p>Figure 1-6</p><p>Your network cables are connected and you are ready to start your network.</p></li></ol></li><li>Start your network in the correct sequence<note><p id="Warning"><b>Warning</b>: Failure to start or restart your network in the correct sequence could prevent you from accessing the Internet.</p></note><ol><li>First, plug in and turn on the cable or DSL modem. Wait 2 minutes.</li><li>Now, plug the power cord into your wireless router and into a power outlet. Wait 1 minute.</li><li><fig id="a5364957"><image href="media/image6.png"/></fig>Last, turn on your computer.<note><p>Note: For DSL customers, if software logs you in to the Internet, do not run thatmsoftware. You may need to go to the Internet Explorer Tools menu, Internet Options, Connections tab page where you can select “Never dial a connection.”</p></note><p><fig id="p6407643"><image href="media/image7.png"/></fig></p><p>Figure 1-7</p></li><li>Check the wireless router status lights to verify the following:</li></ol></li><li>Power: The power light (1) should turn amber and then solid green. If it does not, see <xref href="#_bookmark19">“Quick <b>Tip</b>” on page 2-1</xref>.</li><li>Wireless: The wireless light (2) should be lit after turning on the router.</li><li>Internet: The Internet port light (3) should be lit. If not, make sure the Ethernet cable is securely attached to the wireless router Internet port and the modem, and the modem is powered on.</li><li>LAN: A LAN light (4) should be lit. Green indicates your computer is communicating at 1000 Mbps; amber indicates 10/100 Mbps. If a LAN light is not lit, check that the Ethernet cable from the computer to the router is securely attached at both ends, and that the computer is turned on.</li><li>Connect to the wireless router by typing <xref href="http://www.routerlogin.net/" scope="external" format="html">http://www.routerlogin.net</xref> in the address field of your browser, then click Enter.<p><fig id="a5151673"><image href="media/image8.png"/></fig>Figure 1-8</p><note><p><b>Tip</b>: Connect to the wireless router by typing any one of these three URLs in the address field of your browser, then clicking Enter:</p></note><ul><li>http://www.routerlogin.net</li><li>http://www.routerlogin.com</li><li>http://192.168.1.1</li></ul><note><p><fig id="w4829714"><image href="media/image9.png"/></fig>The wireless router will prompt you to enter the user name of admin and the password. </p></note><p>Figure 1.9</p></li><li>For security reasons, the router has its own user name and password. When prompted, enter <b>admin </b>for the router user name and <b>password </b>for the router password, both in lower case letters.<p>Note: The router user name and password are not the same as any user name or</p><note><p>password you may use to log in to your Internet connection.</p></note><p>After logging in, you will see the menu below<fig id="l4297898"><image href="media/image10.png"/></fig></p><p>Figure 1-10</p><p>If you cannot connect to the wireless router, verify your computer networking setup. It should be set to obtain both IP and DNS server addresses automatically, which is usually so. For help with this, consult the documentation that came with your computer or see the links in <xref href="./appendix_b_related_documents.dita#k7782881/_bookmark42">Appendix B, “Related Documents”</xref>.</p></li><li>Click Next. The wizard will assist you with configuring your wireless router to access the Internet.</li><li>Advanced users who want to manually configure the router can select the No radio button, enter admin and password as the user name and password when prompted, and fill in the required information on the Basic Settings page.</li><li>Click Done to finish.<p>You are now connected to the Internet!</p></li></ol></body></topic>