<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
                            <!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
                            <topic id="u4677249" xml:lang="en-us"><title class="- topic/title " id="_Toc171695893">Wireless Router</title><body><p>The configuration assistant wizard only appears when the router is in its factory default state, and access to the router does not require a login name or password. After you configure the wireless router (or bypass the configuration assistant wizard), it will not appear again, and you will have to log in to the your wireless router to make changes to it.</p><note><p id="Note"><b>Note: </b>The factory default state is restored when you use the factory reset button. See <xref href="#_bookmark36">“Restoring</xref> <xref href="#_bookmark36">the Default Configuration and Password” on page 2-6</xref> for more information on this feature.</p></note><p>To access the router using its login name and password, follow these instructions.</p><ol><li>Connect to the wireless router by typing <xref href="http://www.routerlogin.net/" scope="external" format="html"><b>http://www.routerlogin.net</b></xref><b> </b>in the address field of your browser, then click <b>Enter</b>.<p><fig id="h8599295"><image href="media/image11.png"/></fig>Figure 1-11</p><note><p id="Tip"><b>Tip</b>: Connect to the wireless router by typing any one of these three URLs in the address field of your browser, then clicking Enter:</p></note><ul><li>• http://www.routerlogin.net</li><li>• http://www.routerlogin.com</li><li>• http://192.168.1.1</li></ul><note><p>The wireless router will prompt you to enter the user name of admin and the password.</p></note></li><li>For security reasons, the router has its own user name and password. When prompted, enter admin for the router user name and password for the router password, both in lower case letters.<note><p><b>Note:</b> The router user name and password are not the same as any user name or</p></note></li><li>password you may use to log in to your Internet connection.<p>A login window like the one shown below opens:<fig id="k0548911"><image href="media/image12.png"/></fig></p><p>Figure 1-12</p><p>Enter the user name and password. The wireless router will display its home page.</p><p>When the wireless router is connected to the Internet, click the Knowledge Base or the Documentation link under the Web Support menu to view support information or the documentation for the wireless router.</p><p>If you do not click Logout, the wireless router will wait 5 minutes after there is no activity before it automatically logs you out.</p></li></ol></body></topic>